http://www.aggienetwork.com/privacy/

How Your Gift is Used
Contact Our Annual Giving Team Make a Gift!
Privacy Policy
The Association of Former Students (The Association) is committed to serving the Aggie Network and Texas A&M University. We are here to extend your Aggie experience long after you leave campus. While information about you is fundamental to our ability to do this, we fully recognize the importance of keeping personal information secure. Because we respect your right to privacy, we have always placed a high priority on protecting the personal information you provide us. We want you to understand our information safeguards, the information we collect, the information we share and the benefits when we share information about you.
This privacy statement covers the site www.AggieNetwork.com. Topics covered are:
What personally identifiable information The Association collects.
What organization collects the information.
How The Association uses the information.
With whom The Association may share user information.
What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information.
What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under The Association control.
How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information.
If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, they should first contact our Web team by email at Web@AggieNetwork.com or by phone at (979) 845-7514.
Information Collection and Use:
Information Collection
As part of our mission to support Texas A&M University, The Association and the Texas A&M Foundation maintain a joint database of Former Student and donor records. The Association collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site. Information provided to The Association and stored in the unified database is accessible to the Texas A&M Foundation. For information on how the Texas A&M Foundation may use this information, please review their privacy policy.
Registration
In order to use certain aspects of this Web site, a user must first complete the registration form. During registration a user is required to give contact information (such as first name, last name, class year, ID (UIN, Aggie ID or last 4 digits of your social security number) and email address (if available)). We use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which he/she has expressed interest. It is optional, but encouraged for the user to provide demographic information (such as marital status and gender), and unique identifiers (such as, username and password), so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site.
Donation
We request information from the user on our donation form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, email, and billing address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customers' donations. If we have trouble processing a donation, the information is used to contact the user. If you choose to make a donation to The Association with a credit card, your credit card number will be processed by a secure third-party service, Stripe. Credit card numbers are not stored on any of The Association’s servers.
Other Sources
The Association also collects information from the following sources:
Texas A&M University Student Information Management System. (SIMS)
Information you provide to us through forms, correspondence, newsletters or communication with us including telephone and the Internet.
Noteworthy news items provided by local A&M Clubs or third party news services.
US Postal Service Change of Address Service
Companies that perform marketing services on our behalf.
Information Use
Profile
We store information that we collect through cookies and log files. A profile is stored information that we keep on individual users that details their viewing preferences. This profile is used to tailor a user’s visit to our Web site. We do not share your profile with other third parties.
Cookies
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s computer tied to information about the user. To protect your privacy, cookies that include personally identifiable information are transmitted over secure channels. Some cookies, like the one that enables you to stay logged in, don’t expire when you close the browser if you have used the “remember me” feature.
Web Analytics
You can browse our Web site without giving us any personal information. We use web analytic technology, including specifically Google Analytics and Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, to help us analyze traffic to the Sites in order to understand visitors’ interests and to continually update our Site to improve a user’s experience. Visit Google’s Privacy Policy to learn how Google Analytics collects and processes data. You may choose to engage Google Analytics’ currently available opt-outs for the web.
Third Party Advertising
This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by AggieNetwork.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.
Log Files
Like most standard Web site servers we use log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.
Communications from the Site
AggieNews from The Association
If a user wishes to subscribe to our email newsletter, we ask for contact information such as name and email address. Out of respect for our users privacy we provide a way to opt-out of these communications. Please see the Choice/Opt-out section.
Service and Administrative Communications
On occasion, it might be necessary for us to send out a service-related announcement to provide you with information that may affect your use of our Web site or your personal privacy. We also automatically send administrative emails when you take certain actions, such as changing your password. Service and administrative communications are not promotional in nature and users cannot unsubscribe from them.
The "Find an Aggie" Tool (Online Directory of Former Students):
Accessibility
The "Find an Aggie" tool is accessible only to registered users of AggieNetwork.com. Your personal information is kept in a secure database that is only accessible to The Association staff and the Texas A&M Foundation (please see Information Collection for information on joint database with the Texas A&M Foundation). After registering with AggieNetwork.com you have the ability to set your own privacy settings for the information that is displayed in the Online Directory. If the suppression does not meet your requirements, you can email Records@AggieNetwork.com and we will be glad to ensure that your information is not displayed anywhere on AggieNetwork.com. All requests made to The Online Directory are encrypted with TLS level encryption.
Use and Sharing of Information
The Association collects and uses your personal information to operate AggieNetwork.com and the “Find an Aggie” tool. The information displayed in the Online Directory (database) contains fields such as your name, address, zip code, phone number, employer, and other statistics regarding you. By default, your phone number, and email address are hidden.
The Association does not sell, rent or lease the database to non-partner third parties. The Association may, from time to time, share data with third-party business partners and affiliates who will contact you about a particular offering that may be of interest to you, including, but not limited to, corporate partners and travel providers for the Traveling Aggies program. In addition, The Association may share data with trusted partners to help us send you email or postal mail, distribute the Texas Aggie magazine, produce and print a hard copy Directory of Former Students, provide customer support or arrange for deliveries. All third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide the services agreed upon by The Association and each party is required to sign a security agreement and maintain the confidentiality of your information.
The Association also provides a verification service using the database to TexAgs.com for their AgTag program. TexAgs.com does not have access to the database and verification is made through an automated secure online verification process developed by The Association.
To request that we do not share your information with third-party business partners or affiliates, please contact The Association's Records team at (979) 845-7514 or Records@AggieNetwork.com.
Record Limit
In order to ensure that the database is not compromised by any third party, we have limited the basic results returned to 30 at a time for up to 25,000 records (detailed results are limited to 500 per day). This limits one person from downloading the entire directory to their computer and then selling the list to advertising companies. This also helps keep the load speed of AggieNetwork.com at a reasonable level.
Information Use
The "Find an Aggie" tool is not intended for marketing or political purposes. If The Association has reason to believe that any user is utilizing the Directory for unauthorized purposes, The Association will terminate that users’ access to the Directory immediately. If you have questions about usage of the Directory, or if you feel you have been solicited as a result of your inclusion in the Directory, please contact The Association's web team at (979) 845-7514 or Web@AggieNetwork.com.
Email Privacy
Personal Email Accounts
The Association is very protective of your email address. We do not sell or give email addresses away. We do use email to stay in touch with you, and if you so desire it is placed in the Online Directory of Former Students so that other Former Students can email you through our Web site (your email information will not be displayed). If you do not want Former Students to be able to contact you via email through our site, you can change your email address to "Private" in your account settings.
The Association will use only use this email to send official correspondence and approved emails on behalf of organizations it recognizes. These include Texas A&M, A&M Clubs, Classes and some other groups such as colleges. In addition, a select group of partner affiliates also send emails using The Association’s email system; however, they do not have direct access to email addresses. These emails are targeted to a specific audience.
@AggieNetwork.com Email Accounts
The Association provides lifetime email addresses using Google Apps. Google provides site administrators with a way to perform automated "email audits" to review emails of users. The Association does not use this feature and will never access your account without your permission. Staff members who are administrators of the @AggieNetwork.com email system can help you with technical aspects of your account, including initial setup and password resets, but they cannot log into your account or read emails.
Disclaimers
Legal Disclaimer
Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site.
Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)
We do not share any aggregate information with any third party advertisers or any other party.
Third Party Advertisers
The Association does NOT share Web site usage information about users.
Choice/Opt-out
Users who no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications may opt-out of receiving these communications by using the link at the bottom of each piece of communication, or the user may contact us at (979) 845-7514, by mail at 505 George Bush Drive, College Station, Texas 77840-2918 or by email at Records@AggieNetwork.com to opt-out.
Links
This Web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, The Association, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.
Security
This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When users submit sensitive information via the Web site, their information is protected both online and off-line.
When our registration/donation form asks users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted and is protected with the best encryption software in the industry. While on a secure page, such as our donation form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are just ‘surfing’.
While we use TLS/1.0 and TLS/1.1 encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users’ information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, records processing and our web team) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment, in a locked facility.
If users have any questions about the security at our Web site, users can send an email to Web@AggieNetwork.com.
Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information
If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or deactivate users’ personally identifiable information. This can be done by logging in and clicking "Your Aggie Profile" link at the top right of each page, or by emailing our Records Team at Records@AggieNetwork.com, by phone at (979) 845-7514 or by mail at:
The Association of Former Students
Attn: Records Processing
505 George Bush Drive
College Station, Texas 77840-2918
Notification of Changes
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.
If, however, we are going to use users’ personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users via email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our Web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.
Contact Information
If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:
Phone:
(979) 845-7514
Fax:
(979) 845-9263
E-Mail:
Web@AggieNetwork.com
Postal Address:
When Aggies see a need, their energy and their selflessness draw others into the cause, and good things happen.
© 2020 The Association of Former Students of Texas A&M University, All Rights Reserved
505 George Bush Drive
College Station, TX 77840
(979) 845-7514
When Aggies see a need, their energy and their selflessness draw others into the cause, and good things happen.
© 2020 The Association of Former Students of Texas A&M University, All Rights Reserved
×Close
